

MATEUS FIORI, MSC

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

• Avaré-SP - Brazil

J +55 (14) 9 8104-7858

in linkedin.com/in/mateusfiori

sithub.com/mateusfiori

Profile

Download PDF

Machine Learning Engineer with a Master's degree in Computational Intelligence by São Paulo State University (UNESP) with great interest and experience in topics such as Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Software Engineering as a whole. Highly organized and motivated by the countless challenges provided by the area.

Experience

Neoway | Uma empresa B3

12/2021 - Current

Machine Learning Engineer

Implemented MLOps culture inside the Data Science team.

Models and services deployment.

DAG development for data pipeline.

Planned and developed model monitoring structure.

Conducted tech courses for team members.

Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

Clear communication among teams.

Finch Soluções

06/2020 - 12/2021

Data Scientist

Planned, developed and maintained data science software services to enhance specific internal processes.

Developed natural language processing and machine/ deep learning models.

Exploratory data analysis.

Conducted tech courses for team members.

Investigated available resources to develop more useful project plans.

Completed reviews of codes, requirements and project plans.

Designed and developed scalable and optimized APIs using Python / FastAPI in order to turn the created models available to external usage.

New Way Soluções Digitais

05/2019 - 06/2020

Software Engineer

Squad leader.

Planned and developed microservices solution to integrate company's main solution.

Tasks planning and management.

New Way Soluções Digitais

06/2018 - 05/2019

Full Stack Web Developer

Developed and maintained features for company's main solution.

Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.

New Way Soluções Digitais

06/2018 - 05/2019

Mentor

Provided guidance on learning Python programming language. Provided exercises and projects to improve learning.

Data Classification Supervisor

Managed 6 people team with the goal of classifying a large amount of natural language data. Data corpus classified successfully.

Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

New Way Soluções Digitais

Data Classification Intern

Data classification in general.

08/2017 - 03/2018

Jr.com - Empresa Junior de Computação de Bauru

Vice President

Managed a group of student directors.

Created company's legal documentation along with the President.

01/2016 - 03/2017

Skills

AI Model Development

Very well experienced on developing a wide variety of machine learning models to solve business problems.

Communication and Proactivity

Oustanding team work ability having empathy and clear communication. Open minded and always open to learn something new.

System Engineering

Microservice engineering from planning to production, prioritizing organization and clean/intuitive code.

Leadership

Comfortable and experienced on having a leading position. Proven ability to work with people. Great active listener.

Agile

Proven ability and experienced on working in an agile (Scrum) team. Deep understanding of the scrum cerimonies.

Teaching and Learning

Curious and fast learner. Proven ability to teach and/or explain theoretical concepts about software engineering and artificial intelligence.

Technical

Python	Machine/Deep Learning	REST-RESTful
Docker	Natural Language Processing	Kubernetes
SQL / NoSQL	Linux	Software Design
GIT	Data Science	Airflow

Education

São Paulo State University - UNESP

Computer Science

São Paulo State University - UNESP

Master Degree - Computational Intelligence